Kamau Samuel

□ +2547 0821-2968 | ✓ gachungasamuel54@gmail.com | ⊙ treezy254 | 🛅 kamau-samuel

Summary

Software Engineer, Full Stack Developer, and Honors Computer Science student with 3+ years of experience. Engaged, creative third-year student eager to learn; Interested in creating interesting user-oriented solutions for real-world problems and learning new technologies.

Programming Languages: C++, Python, Java, Javascript, HTML, CSS, SQL Technology: Git, Unix, Flask, AWS, ETL, Virtual Reality, React, Data Science

Work Experience _____

Savana Nairobi, **Kenya**

INTERN, SOFTWARE ENGINEER

July 2022 - Current

- · Contributed to front-end development tasks, including user interface designs and providing detailed documentation.
- Conducted software testing and quality assurance procedures as well as executing API testing protocols.
- · Completed several projects including the NCC intranet solution as well as the Jenny Online clothing shop.

KCA University, Nairobi Nairobi, Kenya

UNDERGRADUATE RESEARCH ASSISTANT 2023

May 2019 - December

- · Implemented file readers/writers for JSON inputs/outputs to match system architecture properties
- Refactor large components of code to adapt to new libraries and class structures
- Implemented a continuous status flag printing system to expedite debugging, testing, and readability

ASSISTANT INSTRUCTOR June 2019 - July 2022

- · Mentor and coach secondary school students in introductory Python and Web development
- Construct programming demonstrations to showcase basic console output, class structure, and functions
- 100+ deployable first-time programmer student projects

Projects

BAZU | OCT. 2023

- · A Large Language Model powered system that converts simple prompts into fully developed systems.
- · Develops web applications and mobile applications with great ease and of good quality.

AUTO DATA | APR. 2023

- A UI dashboard for simplifying the Data Science process.
- · Developed in Streamlit-ui and Python for no code data ETL and Modelling. Tested on several Kaggle datasets.

INTERACTIVE SCREENCASTS | JUNE. 2022

- · A platform that supports interactive screencasts for faster and efficient learning.
- Reduces time to learn new programming languages by 50%.

ALGRORITHMIC TRADING | JAN. 2022

- · An algorithmic trading system that utilizes sentiment analysis from twitter and data sources to make predictions.
- · Provides an annual return of 120% net profits.

Academic Involvement

KCAU-TECH CLUB Nairobi, Kenya

VICE PRESIDENT

May. 2022 - PRESENT

- · Reformed the society focusing on software engineering and building networks on and off campus by strengthening student and faculty bonds
- · Optimized management to optimize drastic growth in member involvement following our annual 100+ attendee hackathon
- · Mentored and trained the next generation of software engineering leaders in professional, academic, and technical development

Education

KCA University Nairobi, Kenya

B.S. IN SOFTWARE DEVELOPMENT 2023

May. 2019 - Dec

- · Cumulative GPA: 3.82
- Artificial Intelligence CS50